(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-30T12:41:18.411205",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
御伽話は さっき死んだみたい
Fairy tales seem to have died just now,
煉瓦の病棟でうまく歌えなくて
unable to sing well in the brick hospital.
霧に煙る夜浮かべ赤い月
A red moon floats in the fog-shrouded night.
ほらみて 私を 目を逸らさないで
Look at me, don't look away.
黒い鉄格子の中で
Inside the black iron bars,
私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born into this world.
悪意の代償を願え
Wish for the price of malice,
望むがままにお前に
exactly as you desire,
さあ与えよう正義を
I will grant you justice.
壊して 壊される前に
Destroy before you are destroyed,
因果の代償を払い
pay the price of cause and effect,
共に行こう 名前もない怪物
and let's go together, nameless monster.
耳鳴りがして
My ears are ringing
鉄柵のベッドで
in the iron-barred bed.
思い出せないの あの日の旋律
I can't remember that day's melody.
雨はまだやまない
The rain still hasn't stopped,
何にも見えないの
and I can't see a thing.
ほらみて こんなに大きくなったの
Look, I've grown this big.
黒い雨降らせこの空
Make this sky rain black rain,
私は望まれないもの
I am something unwanted.
ひび割れたノイローゼ
A cracked neurosis,
愛す同罪の傍観者達に
to the loving, complicit bystanders.
さあ今振るえ正義を
Now, brandish your justice,
消せない傷を抱きしめて
embracing unerasable wounds.
この身体を受け入れ
Accept this body,
共に行こう 名前もない怪物
and let's go together, nameless monster.
神ハ告グル 真ノ世界ヲ
God proclaims the true world.
黒い鉄格子の中で
Inside the black iron bars,
私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born into this world.
悪意の代償を願え
Wish for the price of malice,
望むがままにお前に
exactly as you desire.
さあ与えよう正義を
I will grant you justice.
壊して 壊される前に
Destroy before you are destroyed,
因果の代償を払い
pay the price of cause and effect,
報いよ 名もなき怪物
reap the reward, nameless monster.
黒い雨降らせこの空
Make this sky rain black rain,
私は望まれないもの
I am something unwanted.
ひび割れたノイローゼ
A cracked neurosis,
共に行こう 名前もない怪物
and let's go together, nameless monster.
御伽話は さっき死んだみたい
The fairy-tale has died just now
煉瓦の病棟で 上手く歌えなくて
In this brick hospital, I can't seem to sing
霧に煙る夜 浮かべ赤い月
The night is foggy, with the floating red moon
ほら見て 私を 目を逸らさないで
Look at me, don't look away from me
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born behind these dark iron bars
悪意の代償を願え 望むがままにお前に
I pray that the evil in you can be amended
さあ与えよう正義を 壊して 壊される前に
So bring justice to me, to destroy this evil before it destroys me
耳鳴りがして 鉄条網絡まって
I hear buzzing in my ears, the tangled wires
思い出せないの あの日の旋律 雨はまだ止まない
I can't remember the melody from that day, the rain still hasn't stopped
何にも見えないの ほら見て こんなに大きくなったの
I can't see anything, but look how big I've grown now
黒い雨降らせこの空 私は望まれないもの
The black rain is falling from this sky, I am a being with no desires
ひび割れたノイローゼ 愛する同罪の傍観者達に
Beloved bystanders with the same sins are cracking from this neurosis
さあ今震える正義を 消せない傷を抱きしめて
Now, trembling justice, embrace my unerasable scars
この身体を受け入れ 共に行こう 名前のない怪物
Accept this body and we'll go together, nameless monster
神は告ぐる 真の世界を
Ah, the new world that god spoke of...
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born behind these dark iron bars
はい！ということで皆さん、こんばんはぴえーーーい！
Yes! So everyone, good evening pie~r!
お誕生日ですね！
Today is my birthday!
本日はお誕生日ですね、と自分でお祝いします！
Celebrating my own birthday today!
ちょっと待って、水飲もっかな。水飲も。
Hold on, let me drink some water. Drinking water.
ばっちゃる、ばっちゃるウォーター。
Virtual, virtual water.
ということで、今日はトワ様のお誕生日です！
So today is Towa-sama's birthday!
みんな見てる？って言うか待機所でさ、TMT映しすぎだから！やめて！ちょっと！
Are you guys watching? I mean, in the waiting room, you're showing TMT too much! Stop it! Hey!
もう今年はほら、TMTを脱出するっていう話をさしてたから、みんながそれをやめないと終わらないわけでしょう？
As I was saying this year we need to escape TMT, so if you guys don't stop, it won't end, right?
やめてください本当に！最低ですよ！ドン！
Please stop, really! That's the worst! Bam!
っていうのを1人でやるのもすごいとても寂しいんですけどね（笑）
Doing this all by myself is super lonely too, though.
はい、あの最初歌った、あ、曲はね「名前のない怪物」を歌っていただきました！
Right, the first song we sang, ah, the song was "Namae no Nai Kaibutsu"!
イェーイ！今日はね、トワはこの後もう1曲ソロで歌って、そのあとにゲストパートに行くんですけども
Yay! Today, Towa will sing one more solo after this, and then go to the guest part, but...
今日はね、かっこいい曲から可愛い曲まで準備しているので、ぜひぜひ最後まで聴いていってもらえると嬉しいです！
Today, we've prepared everything from cool songs to cute songs, so I hope you'll listen all the way to the end!
あとこれ、トワ闇と、生誕祭2021、これいっぱいつぶやいてね！イェイ！イェイイェイ！
And also this, "#TowaBirthday2021", tweet it a lot! Yay! Yay yay!
ということでね、ちょっと落ち着いてから次の曲に行きたいと思います。
With that, I'd like to calm down a bit before moving on to the next song.
教えて 教えてよ その仕組みを 僕の中に誰がいるの?
Tell me, tell me how this all works; who lies within me?
壊れた 壊れたよ この世界で 君が笑う 何も見えずに
I'm broken, broken amidst this world. But you're smiling, blind to it all.
壊れた僕なんてさ 息を止めどけない もう ほどけないよ
I'm broken anyway, so I halt my breath; I can't unravel myself...
真実さえ freeze 壊せる 壊せない 狂える 狂えない
...even the truth's in a freeze. I can break this — it's unbreakable — I'll go insane...
あなたを見つけて 揺れた 歪んだ世界にだんだん僕は透き通って見えなくなって
Then I found you — and felt something give way! In this twisted world, my form grows transparent...
教えて 教えてよ その仕組みを
Tell me how this structure works?
僕の中に誰がいるの？
Who is inside of me?
壊れた 壊れたよ この世界で 君が笑う 何も見えずに
Broken in this world where you smile.
壊れた僕なんてさ 息を止めて
A broken me... holding my breath.
ほどけない もう ほどけないよ 真実さえ freeze
Unraveling, even truth is frozen.
壊せる 壊せない 狂える 狂えない
Breakable, unbreakable, crazy.
あなたを見つけて 揺れた
Finding you, I shook.
歪んだ世界にだんだん僕は透き通って見えなくなって
In a distorted world, I fade away.
見つけないで 僕のことを 見つめないで
Don't find me, don't look at me.
誰かが描いた世界の中で あなたを傷つけたくはないよ
In someone's world, I won't hurt you.
覚えていて 僕のことを 鮮やかなまま
Remember me just as I was.
無限に広がる孤独が絡まる 無邪気に笑った記憶が刺さって
Endless loneliness, piercing memories.
動けない 動けない 動けない 動けない 動けない 動けないよ
I can't move anymore.
変わってしまった 変えられなかった
It changed, it couldn't be changed.
2つが絡まる 2人が滅びる
Two intertwine, two perish.
壊せる 壊せない 狂える 狂えない
Breakable, unbreakable, crazy.
あなたを傷つけないよ
I won't hurt you.
揺れた 歪んだ世界にだんだん僕は透き通って見えなくなって
In a distorted world, I fade away.
見つけないで 僕のことを 見つめないで
Don't find me, don't look at me.
誰かが仕組んだ孤独な罠に 未来がほぐれてしまう前に
Before futures unravel in a lonely trap...
思い出して 僕のことを 鮮やかなまま
Remember me just as I was.
忘れないで 忘れないで 忘れないで 忘れないで
Don't forget, don't forget...
変わってしまったことにparalyze 変えられないことだらけのparadise
Paralyzed by change, a paradise of odds.
覚えていて 僕のことを
Remember me.
教えて 教えて 僕の中に誰がいるの？
Tell me, who is inside of me?
Suspect
[Title: Suspect]
イタズラに君をずっと見ていたわけじゃない
I haven't just been watching you.
僕の考えを当ててごらんよ
Try guessing what I'm thinking.
ささやかな仕草 視線 瞬き 君はもう掌に
Subtle gestures—you're in my palm.
剥ぎ出しの trap なんてかかる訳ないわ
No way I'd fall for a bare trap.
甘い言葉にも惑わされない
I won't be swayed by sweet words.
心の奥の奥の奥まで見透かしちゃうよ
I'll see right through your heart.
近くなる流星を思い通りに君は動かす
You move the approaching meteor.
常世の闇に囚われたまま 奏でる悲鳴を
Trapped in the eternal darkness, play me your wails
さあ 爪を研いだなら
Now, if you sharpen your claws
まだ子供のようなあなたのために
for someone still like a child,
ああ 試されたいなら
Ah, if you want to be tested,
その愚かな手に手錠をかけて
put handcuffs on those foolish hands.
常世の闇に囚われたまま 甘い甘いガムを噛んでた
Trapped in the eternal darkness, chewing sweet, sweet gum,
いくつかの後悔を捧げて
offering up so many regrets.
さりげない合図に隠された
Hidden in a casual signal,
答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
I'll make you understand the answer right away.
微笑みな嘘にまみれた
Immersed in a smiling lie,
拒んだままに 受け入れてあげる
just as you refused, I'll accept it for you,
ほら悲鳴を聞かせて
look, let me hear your wails.
さあ 指を鳴らしたら
Now, if you snap your fingers,
この子猫のような私のために
for someone like me, like this kitten,
ああ 喉が渇いたわ
Ah, my throat is parched,
薄紅の口に指を散らして
scattering my fingers across pale crimson lips.
狭い牢獄に閉じ込めたまま 首輪に繋がれたいの?
Locked away in a narrow prison, do you want to be chained to a collar?
くだらないルールじゃ奪えない
Useless rules cannot steal it away;
自由はすでにこの手の中にある
freedom is already in these hands.
愛情では測れない
It cannot be measured by affection,
弱ったままに選ばせてあげる ほら心を開いて
let you choose while you're weak, come on, open your heart.
わからないふりをして寝ぼけてるの?
Acting clueless, are you still half-asleep?
もっと熱い闇を見せて? ねぇ
Show me a more passionate darkness, won't you?
さりげない合図に隠された
Hidden in a casual signal,
答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
I'll make you understand the answer right away.
微笑みな嘘にまみれた
Immersed in a smiling lie,
拒んだままに 受け入れてあげる
just as you refused, I'll accept it for you.
常世の闇に刻むこの名を
Carving this name into the eternal darkness,
わからせてあげる ほら悲鳴を聞かせてよ
I'll make you understand, come on, let me hear your wails.
夢見ないで
Don't dream,
ほら聞かせて
come on, let me hear it.
気がついてるんでしょ?
You've noticed by now, haven't you?
ここにいる意味さえも
Even the meaning of being here,
切り札はそれぞれ 互いの手札に
our trump cards are each in each other's hands.
頭と心で暴き出して
Uncover them with mind and heart,
胸を打ち抜け
shoot right through my chest.
自覚のないしょ? ねぇ 思い通りに
You're unaware of it, aren't you? Just as you wish,
君は動かされていること
you are being made to move.
単純じゃないの 駆け引きのヒントを
It's not so simple, hints to the bargaining—
すべてひろって
gather them all up.
唯一無二のジョーカーにすることで理解できた愛の形を
By making you the one and only joker, I could understand the shape of love,
どこかの誰かに仕組まれていても
even if it was plotted by someone, somewhere.
最後に笑う君と
With you smiling at the end,
さあ 指を鳴らしたら
now, if you snap your fingers,
この子猫のような私のために
for someone like me, like this kitten,
ああ 喉が渇いたわ
Ah, my throat is parched,
薄紅の口に指を散らして
scattering my fingers across pale crimson lips.
真実線は次のステージへ
The line of truth moves to the next stage.
はい、ということで、コラボ
Yeah, so, this collaboration...
ということで、ゲストはどこだ?
...is here, so where are the guests?
あれ、どこだ?
Huh, where are they?
最初からさ、かき回してくれた
Right from the start, stirring things up—
どこだ、どこだ?
where are they, where are they?
ふぶき見つけあげるよ
Fubuki, we're gonna find you!
主役よね、ちょっと主役よ。
You're the main star, right? Sort of the main star.
ということで、コラボもね、最初の
So, for the collab too, the very first...
コラボは吹雪先輩と、ミオちゃんに来てもらいました!
...collaboration brought Fubuki-senpai and Mio-chan!
とわみけ、とわみけー!
Towa-Mike, Towa-Mike!
え、ちっちゃ? とわはちっちゃい!
Eh, so small? Towa is tiny!
ちっちゃいね、よしよしよしよし。
Tiny, aren't you? There, there, there.
え?
Eh?
今日の晩御飯は?
What's for dinner today?
今日のパンツ? 先輩に踏み回されてるって!
Today's underwear? You're being trampled on by your senior!
いや、実はこういった3Dレッスンで先輩たちとコラボするっていうのは
No, actually, doing a 3D collaboration like this with senpais...
初めてに近い。いやそうかも。しかもミオちゃんと吹雪先輩、どっちも3D。
...is close to a first for me. Yeah, maybe. And both Mio-chan and Fubuki-senpai are in 3D.
いや、そうだね。初めてだよ。
Yeah, that's right! It's a first.
初めてで、いやいや、これをさ、ちょっとトワ様に言いたいことがあったんですよ。
It's a first, and well, I wanted to say something to Towa-sama about this.
え? ここわーい!
Eh? Wait here!
なに、なに、なに、なに、いいですか? はい、なに? あのですね、
What, what, what, is it okay? Yes, what? Well, you see...
ふぶちゃって呼んでくれませんか?
Won't you call me "Fubu-chan"?
えー!? マジで!?
Eh?! Seriously?!
そう、なんかね、後輩たちにね、そう。先輩って呼ばれるのがさ、なんかくすぐったくてさ、ふぶちゃって呼んでるから。
Yeah, you see, the juniors call me that. It feels ticklish to be called "senpai," so they call me "Fubu-chan."
だから、トワ様にも、ぜひね、そう。ふぶちゃんとかふぶきまち。なんかね、もう呼び捨てされたい!
So, I definitely want Towa-sama to call me "Fubu-chan" or "Fubuki-machi." I want to be called by my name without honorifics!
え、じゃあうちは逆に吹雪先輩って呼んだほうが...
Eh, then maybe I should call you Fubuki-senpai instead...
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
ふぶき先輩？
Fubuki-senpai?
じゃあスタート！
Then let's start!
みおちゃんもだし
And Mio-chan too...
ちょうど、みおだけじゃんけんいいなー
Right, a Mio-only janken would be nice~
え、ずるい！ずるいずるい！
No fair! So unfair!
今日からはもう
From today onwards...
ふぶきちゃんか...ふぶきちゃんがいいな でも ふぶきちゃんがふぶきちゃん
Fubuki-chan or... Fubuki-chan would be nice. But Fubuki-chan is Fubuki-chan.
えい！えい！えい！やった！やった！やった！
Ei! Ei! Ei! Yay! Yay! Yay!
え、これプレゼント？
Eh, is this a present?
じゃじゃんプレゼント？
Ta-da, a present?
えい！えい！えい！やった！やった！やった！やったー！
Ei! Ei! Ei! Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay!
せーので！やったー！
On the count of! Yay!
えぶみおでーす！えー！
We are Ebu-Mio! Yay!
こんなんでよかったのかな？よかったのかな？
Was this okay? Was it okay?
じゃあ行くぞ、ふぶき帰るぞ。
Then let's go, Fubuki, time to go home.
帰ろ！
Let's go home!
はいよ、行くぞえい！
Alright, let's go, ei!
色づく想いは刹那
Passions burn for a moment,
百花繚乱花吹雪
a flurry of cherry blossoms.
パッと咲いて散った花は終わり実をつけてく
Flowers pop, bloom, and scatter, bearing fruit at the end.
その時を待てど暮らせど事は進まず
Waiting and living for that time, yet nothing progresses.
そっと触れて知った胸の中の温かさを
Gently touching and knowing the warmth within my heart,
初めてのこの気持ちだけ抱きしめていたい
I want to hold close this feeling for the very first time.
暁交わした約束は“本物”だってきっと
The promise made at dawn is surely the "real deal,"
信じてる
I believe in it.
いろはにほへとぬる香に魅せられた少女たち
Girls charmed by the fragrant colors,
ああはらりほらり はらり落ちる花弁と舞い踊れ
Ah, fluttering, drifting down, dancing with falling petals.
わがよたそでも思い言の葉に込めてみた
Putting my thoughts into words amidst this fleeting world,
誰も皆焦がれる現世の理よ
That is the worldly law everyone yearns for.
色づく想いは刹那 百花繚乱花吹雪
Passions burn for a moment, a flurry of blossoms.
フッと吹き消した夜を灯す月明かりに
In the moonlight lighting up the night blown out in a puff,
曖昧な心が揺れて声は響かず
An uncertain heart wavers and no voice echoes.
もっと触れ立て夢をなぞる指先さえ
Even fingertips tracing dreams with more touch
いつの日か馳せた想い出カタチを忘れかけてた
Had begun to forget the shape of memories once chased.
浮世の波に揺蕩う時うたかたの夢は
When swaying in the waves of the floating world, fleeting dreams
弾けていく
Burst apart.
うものおくやまに荒れる想い達は純情
Passions raging deep in the mountains are pure-hearted.
そうのらりくらり 心揺らめき歌うは雪月花
Yes, wandering aimlessly, hearts wavering, singing of snow, moon, and flowers.
あさきゆめみしと思い踏み込むこの世界は
Stepping into this world with thoughts of fleeting dreams,
誰も皆焦がれる現世の理よ
That is the worldly law everyone yearns for.
色づく想いは刹那
Passions burn for a moment,
百花繚乱花吹雪
a flurry of blossoms.
一二三数えて ここにさあおいで
Counting one, two, three, come here now.
暁交わした約束は“本物”だってきっと
The promise made at dawn is surely the "real deal,"
信じてる
I believe in it.
いろはにほへとぬる香に魅せられた少女たち
Girls charmed by the fragrant colors,
ああはらりほらり はらり落ちる花弁と舞い踊れ
Ah, fluttering, drifting down, dancing with falling petals.
わがよたそでも思い言の葉に込めてみた
Putting my thoughts into words amidst this fleeting world,
誰も皆焦がれる現世の理よ
That is the worldly law everyone yearns for.
色づく想いは刹那
Passions burn for a moment,
百花繚乱
a hundred flowers blooming,
花吹雪
a flurry of blossoms.
風に舞う
Dancing in the wind,
乙女の純情
maidens' pure hearts,
咲き誇れ
blooming proudly.
一歩踏み数えて
Counting steps one by one,
ここにさあおいで
come here now.
あさきゆめみしと思い踏み込むこの世界は
Stepping into this world with thoughts of fleeting dreams,
本物だってきっと信じてる
Surely believing it is the real deal.
いろはにほへとぬる香に魅せられた少女たち
Girls charmed by the fragrant colors,
ああはらりほらり はらり落ちる花弁と舞い踊れ
Ah, fluttering, drifting down, dancing with falling petals.
わがよたそでも思い言の葉に込めてみた
Putting my thoughts into words amidst this fleeting world,
誰も皆焦がれる現世の理よ
That is the worldly law everyone yearns for.
色づく想いは刹那 百花繚乱花吹雪
Passions burn for a moment, a flurry of blossoms.
一二三数えて ここにさあおいで
Counting one, two, three, come here now.
暁交わした約束は“本物”だってきっと信じてる
The promise made at dawn is surely the "real deal."
いろはにほへとぬる香に魅せられた少女たち
Girls charmed by the fragrant colors,
ああはらりほらり はらり落ちる花弁と舞い踊れ
Ah, fluttering, drifting down, dancing with falling petals.
はーー！
Haーー!
パタパタパタ
Flutter flutter flutter
いやこれセンスで踊るの楽しーね！
Man, dancing this with sense is so much fun!
大人な感じだったかな？
Did it feel a bit mature?
大人？
Mature?
あれ？誰が？
Huh? Who?
誰が... あきろぜが？
Who is it... Akirose?
あきろぜだ！
It's Akirose!
あき先輩はねえ、
Aki-senpai is, well...
え、とは、とは？
Eh, Towa, Towa?
え、その次がまつりで、
Eh, next is Matsuri,
来年ね、来年は私にお姉ちゃんを！
Next year, you know, give me an older sister next year!
え？あれ？どういうこと？
Eh? Huh? What do you mean?
てことで、今年も一番そう、お隣に近づいた？
So, this year too, you got closest next door?
そう、
Yeah.
なの？このターミナルじゃないかな？
Is that so? Isn't it this terminal?
あ、言われた！
Ah, you said it!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
百カロラ、花粉吹雪をね、
Hyakucalora, a blizzard of pollen,
まつりちゃんと、あき先輩と、
Matsuri-chan, Aki-senpai, and
はい。
Yes.
歌いました！
we sang!
イェーイ！楽しかった！
Yay! It was fun!
また、ちょっと来年も、こうやってね呼んでいただけたら、お祝いいたしますのでね。
Also, if you invite us like this next year, we'll celebrate.
来年はなんか大人の魅力がある人呼ぼっかな？
Next year, maybe I'll invite someone with adult charm?
あら、ありがとう！
Oh, thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あき先輩、うん、まあね。
Aki-senpai, yeah, well.
そのさ、大人の魅力って？
About that, what is adult charm?
え？
Eh?
祭りさ、大人の魅力って言ったら、お酒とか見てんじゃねえよ！
Matsuri, when you say adult charm, don't look at alcohol!
おいおいおいおいおい！
Hey hey hey hey hey!
え、だってタバコほら、あれじゃあ、靴ほしいとか言ってたから、まあ買ってあげようか、先輩だからね。
Eh, but cigarettes, see, she said she wanted shoes, so I'll buy them for her, since she's a senior.
そしたらね、急に、来年、うん、来年呼んでくれてもいいよ。
And then, suddenly, "You can invite me next year, you know."
いや靴なんて買ってくれなくたって、一緒にやりましょう！
No, even without buying shoes, let's do it together!
よかった！
Great!
後輩をお金で買収する
Buying juniors with money...
見てしまうところなんじゃない
...isn't that what you see?
とう、めちゃめちゃ恥ずかしい！
Towa is super embarrassed!
いや、よく頑張った！
No, I tried hard!
はい、ということで、いつもお世話になってるおふたりとのコラボでした！
Yes, so, it was a collab with the two who always take care of me!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
迷子星 今日も見ている
いつもと変わらない笑顔
纏う それは仮面か
A lost star is looking today too
With the same unchanging smile
Is that mask she wears?
本当の自分を隠して 気付かせぬようじゃなく
怯えるほど 臆病なリアル
Hiding her true self so no one notices
A reality so timid it's frightening
偽りは It's on a scene 真実を Open my heart
Falseness is on a scene, open my heart to the truth
君にすべてを受け止めて欲しい
I want you to accept everything about me
加速していく世界で生きてく僕ら
聞き飽きたよ 止められないの 声へ
We live in an accelerating world
I'm tired of hearing it, towards a voice that cannot be stopped
一か六かで決められた運命ならば
逆らうよ 見つけるよ
If it's a fate decided by one-in-six, I will defy it, I will find it
僕である理由
可愛いだけじゃもういられない
The reason I am me
Just being cute is no longer enough
声を上げていくのさ スターダスト
Raising our voices, stardust
あこがれの自分へ精いっぱい
足元見るだけで精一杯
宇宙を走るような僕には
君に触れることはできるのかな
Yearning, pouring my all into myself
Just looking at my feet takes all I have
For someone running through the universe
Can I ever touch you?
Please me Answer
カウントダウンでフィールマイセット
君と恋する心模様
Please me, Answer
Counting down, feel myself
The state of my heart falling in love with you
飛び出せ
Jump out!
加速していく世界で生きてく僕ら
聞き飽きたよ 止められないの 声へ
一か六かで決められた運命ならば
逆らうよ 見つけるよ
We live in an accelerating world
I'm tired of hearing it, towards a voice that cannot be stopped
If it's a fate decided by one-in-six, I will defy it, I will find it
僕である理由
可愛いだけじゃもういられない
立ち向かい戦うよ
いただいた命をそのために
The reason I am me
Just being cute is no longer enough
I will stand and fight
For the life I've been given
スターダスト
それは胸の中に
声は力に変わる
Stardust
It is inside my chest
Voice turns into power
アポロスター
迷うことはない 僕だけの
一筋の 胸に刻んで
Apollo star
There is no hesitation, engraved in my heart as my own single ray
加速していく世界で生きてく僕ら
聞き飽きたよ 止められないの 声へ
We live in an accelerating world
I'm tired of hearing it, towards a voice that cannot be stopped
遠く遠く 見上げる光
Far, far away, the light we look up to
強く強く 連なる奇跡
Stronger and stronger, connected miracles
一つ一つ 星屑になり
One by one, becoming stardust
Starlight 輝き続ける 彗星
Starlight, the comet continuing to shine
夢見る事さえも許されない
Not even dreaming is allowed
深い闇に閉じ込められたって
Even if we're locked away in deep darkness
夜空を照らしている星と共に
Together with the stars illuminating the night sky
君とおれば何も恐くはない
If I'm with you, there's nothing to fear
何度もつまずき 傷ついても
No matter how many times we stumble and get hurt
確かな絆 光差す
A certain bond, light shining through
新たな扉は 夢の欠片
New doors are fragments of dreams
君と駆け抜ける
Running through with you
しーちゃんと おかゆと 歌いましたー！
We sang with Sii-chan and Okayu!
イェーイ！
Yay!
かくかくしてね
Anyway...
何笑ってんの? 距離がやばいって話になってたの、今
What are you laughing at? We were just talking about how the distance is crazy.
距離が?
Distance?
え?
Huh?
え、やっぱカッコよくさ、歌ったあとのギャップみたいなあるじゃん、いま
Well, after singing so coolly, there's that gap, right?
確かに！
True!
距離! 距離! 距離!
The distance! The distance!
そんなことす...
Don't do that...
いやだってもうMC適当でいいっていうかさ
I mean, MC can just be casual, right?
いやいや、そんなことさ、ね?
No, no, come on...
いや、そんな、そんな裏話は今言っちゃいけないじゃん！
You shouldn't be spilling behind-the-scenes talk right now!
なんとね、このふたりは歌ってみた...てかカバーソングをあげようあげよう詐欺、詐欺...詐欺?
We've been talking about doing a cover song together for so long... Scam? Scam?
詐欺? 詐欺? 詐欺?
A scam? A scam? A scam?
確かにね、しーちゃんとの歌ってみたあげようって言ってね、まだあげてない。
True, we said we'd upload a cover with Sii-chan, but we haven't yet.
で、おかゆとも歌ってみたあげようって言って、まだあげてな...
And I said I'd upload one with Okayu, but haven't yet...
詐欺、詐欺三兄弟みたいな感じなんだよね。詐欺兄弟。詐欺三兄弟です。
It's like the Scam Trio. Scam siblings. We're the Scam Trio.
あげようと思いつつあげてません。とゆことで詐欺三兄弟です。ね?
We keep meaning to upload it but haven't. So we're the Scam Trio, right?
どんな、詐欺師の3人がさ、誕生日なんだよね！
And all three of these scammers share a birthday!
おめでとう！いや、誕生日にね、やっと詐欺を終えて、
Happy birthday! Finally finishing our scam on our birthday,
そうだ！3人で歌いましたね！そうだよね！
That's right! We sang together! That's right!
じゃあ、動画を上げましょう！動画上げようね！上げよ上げよ！
Let's upload the video! Let's upload it!
それだ！いやマジで思ってた、ずっと。
Exactly! I've seriously been thinking that all along.
ほんまか? ほんまか? とか言って、詐欺なんじゃないか?
"Really?" "Really?" Or maybe it's a scam?
はい、ということでおかゆと、しーちゃんとねストリート... イェーイ！
Right, so with Okayu and Sii-chan... Stree... Yay!
それじゃあみんな、行くぞー！うぇーい！待って！
Alright everyone, let's go! Yay! Wait!
目合わせ 始まりの合図
Eye contact, the signal to begin
不足したままの意思疎通
Communication remaining insufficient
無意味な称賛 満足げ日照りの見本市
Meaningless praise, a satisfied drought trade fair
歪らに語る新面貌
A new appearance spoken of in distortion
凸凹に振動した鈍い感性に響いた
Resonating with dull sensitivities vibrating unevenly
針付けられた顔が日に日に歪んでいく
The face pinned down distorts day by day
神の気まぐれに潰されたこの盤回しては
Spinning this board crushed by God's whim
刻まれた瑕疵はすり減る靴底
The carved flaws are worn-out shoe soles
答えて 至上主義アドトラック
Answer me, supremacist ad truck
四六時中を掛け回る
Running around round the clock
所詮使い捨ての消耗品だと?
Are we mere disposable consumables after all?
おっと息切れになるなよ
Whoa, don't run out of breath
拳を突き上げてやれ 夜を飲み込む星の瞬き
Raise your fists high, the twinkle of stars swallowing the night
至上主義アドトラック 四六時中を掛け回る
Supremacist ad truck, running around round the clock
所詮使い捨ての消耗品だと? おっと息切れになるなよ
Are we mere disposable consumables? Whoa, don't run out of breath
拳を突き上げてやれ 夜を飲み込む星の瞬き
Raise your fists high, the twinkle of stars swallowing the night
また隅に積み重ねられていく祈り 丸めて投げ放せ
Prayers piling up in the corners again, roll them up and throw them away
最高峰の捕獲競争
The highest peak's capture competition
鋭い追撃板挟み
Sharp pursuit, caught between a rock and a hard place
息詰まる下り 天上窮地の袋小路
Breath-choking descent, a dead end of heavenly crisis
雨にも負けず 風にも負けず
Not losing to the rain, not losing to the wind
錆びついて腐食する情動
Emotions rusting and corroding
軋みを増した歯車は規格外の線へと見切られていく
Gears with increasing squeaks are written off toward out-of-spec lines
変わり映えのない珍奇な落胤はすてまは
Unchanging, bizarre disgraced offspring...
縮こまった枠すり抜ける震える
Slipping through the shrunk-in frame, trembling
答えて 至上主義アドトラック
Answer me, supremacist ad truck
四六時中を掛け回る
Running around round the clock
唯一無二に吊り下げる
Hanging from the one and only
所詮 役立たずの代用品だろ?
After all, we're just useless substitutes, right?
おい 今に見とけよ
Hey, just you wait and see!
パッと仕掛けてやれば
If we make a sudden move,
夜に溺れる星の花
a star flower drowning in the night—
また一つ 指で押し上げていく
once again, pushing it up with our fingers,
伸び良くエスケープさせる
letting it smoothly escape.
疲弊したままの感情
With exhausted emotions,
環状線 逃れる手は
is there any way to escape the loop?
慣らしされた理想
Tamed ideals,
星の窪み 現実 嗚呼 正解を
the hollow of stars, reality... Ah, give us the right answer!
至上主義 アドラック
Supreme-ism Ad-track,
四六時中を駆け回る
running around 24/7.
所詮 使い捨ての消耗品だろ?
After all, we're just disposable commodities, right?
もっといい日になるなよ、きっと 突き上げてやれ
Hoping for a better day, let's thrust it up!
夜を呑み込む星の花
A star flower swallowing the night—
所詮 二つ二つの代用品だろ?
After all, are we just twin substitutes?
おい 今に見とけよ
Hey, just you wait and see!
パッと仕掛けてやれば
If we make a sudden move,
夜に揺蕩う星の花
a star flower drifting in the night—
また空に散りばめられていく
once again scattered across the sky,
光り求め這い上がる
crawling up in search of light!
至上主義 アドラック
Supreme-ism Ad-track!
はーい、ということで！
Alright, so!
400万人記念の至上主義アドラックでした！
That was "Supreme-ism Ad-track" for the 4 million subscribers milestone!
常闇トワの歌ってみたと、かなたと一緒に歌いました！
I sang it together with Tokoyami Towa's cover and Kanata!
いや、とっても難しかったです！
Man, that was super difficult!
おめでとう！ありがとう！最高に難しかった！
Congratulations! Thank you! It was insanely hard!
いやこのね、難しい曲をね、この二人と歌えて凄い良かったです。
Man, I'm so glad I got to sing such a difficult song with these two.
いや本当にね、楽しく歌わせて…ちょっとやばい息がね！
Really, we got to sing it so enjoyably... wait, I'm running out of breath!
引き続き大変だからね、そうそう本当に、楽しかったね。
It's tough continuing right after, yeah, truly, it was fun.
うん、楽しかった。そう、実はさ、そうそう。
Yeah, it was fun. Oh, actually, yeah, yeah.
かなたとはトワは歌ったことあって、一緒に歌ったことがあってね。
Kanata and Towa have sung it together before,
そうそう、ライブとかで。そう、かなたとはためもあるんだよね。
yeah, at lives and stuff. And Kanata and Watame have too.
そう、でもトワとはためは実はないの、ねえ！
But Towa and Watame actually haven't, right?
もしかして…え？実は不仲なんだよね。
Could it be... eh? Actually, we're not on good terms.
不仲説出てるね、あー！私好きだよ、チューして！
Rumors of bad terms are coming out, ah! I love you, kiss me!
逃げろ、トワ！
Run, Towa!
チュウして！チュウして！
Kiss me! Kiss me!
またまた噂が出てた！でも今日はね、実は3人で初めて…
More rumors came out! But today, actually, for the first time the three of us...
とわためも初めてで、歌わせてもらいました！すごく新鮮でしたよ！
Watame and Towa for the first time too, we got to sing it! It was so fresh!
本当に、すごい新鮮だよね。うん、すごい楽しかった！
Truly, it's super fresh. Yeah, it was super fun!
ああ、楽しかった！ありがとう！こちらこそ！
Ah, it was fun! Thank you! Likewise!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
はい、またありがとうございます！最後のしめ続くよ！
Yes, thank you again! The final closing continues!
よお！
Yo!
手を上げて Clap your hands 海の向こうまで
Raise your hands, clap your hands, all the way across the sea!
Clap your hands 届きますように
Clap your hands, hoping it reaches you!
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Clap your hands, clap your hands,
ほら一緒に Everybody!
look, together, everybody!
Clap your hands 空の向こうまで
Clap your hands, all the way across the sky!
Clap your hands 響きますように
Clap your hands, hoping it echoes!
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Clap your hands, clap your hands,
光り差す 僕たちの未来
casting light on our future!
5、4、3、2、1！
5, 4, 3, 2, 1!
今日はトワ様のお誕生日！主役はトワ様！せーのトワ様！お姉ちゃんにおめでとう！
Today is Towa-sama's birthday! The star is Towa-sama! Ready, Towa-sama! Happy birthday to big sis!
初めよ過すたび
Every time we start anew,
まだでも意味ないタイミング
still meaningless timing.
あの魚みたいに swimming swimming
Swimming, swimming like that fish!
引き寄せるのは in
What we draw closer is...
まだ見えないよ maybe この先には何があるの?
Still not visible, maybe what lies ahead?
また早い予定キープ
Keeping a fast schedule again,
追い付く胸熱き
catching up with a passionate heart.
でもその目に止めて thinking thinking
But stopping in our eyes, thinking, thinking,
変えてみせる change it 踏み出すとさ step in
change it, stepping forward, step in!
突っ込んで見せるよ キラキラまに
I'll plunge right in, glittering,
叶う日まで story 繋ぐから
connecting the story until the day it comes true,
だって君に ずっと見てほしいから
because I want you to keep watching me forever!
もっと見てほしいから
Because I want you to look at me more...
手を上げて
Raise your hands,
clap your hands
海の向こうまで
across the sea,
clap your hands
届くように
may it reach you,
手を叩こう
let's clap our hands,
let's clap our hands!
ほら一緒に
C'mon, together,
everybody
clap your hands
空の向こうまで
across the sky,
clap your hands
響きますように
may it resound,
手を叩こう
let's clap our hands,
let's clap our hands!
光射す ぼくたちの未来
Light enters and illuminates our future.
5 4 3 2 1
hololive 5th stars
始めようか さあ diving
Shall we start? C'mon, diving.
待っても意味ない timing
Waiting is pointless timing.
あの魚みたいに swimming swimming
Like those fish, swimming, swimming.
引き寄せるの lighting
Drawing closer with lighting.
まだ見えないよ maybe
Still can't see it yet, maybe.
この先には何があるのか？
What lies ahead of this?
まだ早いよ take it
It's still early, so take it.
追い付く日まで shaking
Shaking until the day we catch up.
でもたまに止まって thinking thinking
But sometimes stopping to think, think.
変えてみせる change
Let's try changing it, change.
踏み出すのさ stepping
Taking a step forward, stepping.
掴んでみるよ キラキラ my dream
Grasping my sparkling dream.
叶える日まで story 繋ぐから
Fantasizing about that story until my dream comes true,
だって君にもっと見てほしいから
because I want you to gaze at me even more.
手を上げて
Raise your hands,
clap your hands
海の向こうまで
across the sea,
clap your hands
届くように
may it reach you,
手を叩こう
let's clap our hands,
let's clap our hands!
ほら一緒に everybody
C'mon, together, everybody,
clap your hands 空の向こうまで
clap your hands, across the sky,
clap your hands 響きますように
clap your hands, may it resound,
手を叩こう
let's clap our hands,
let's clap our hands!
光射す ぼくたちの未来
Light enters and illuminates our future.
今日はいらない ブレーキ
No need for brakes today,
理性壊せ breaking
break your rationality.
何時でもいいでしょ 四六時中 君は何を feeling？
Isn't it fine anytime? 24/7, what are you feeling?
飛び放て sparking
Unleash the sparking,
暗闇に放つ レーザービーム
laser beams shot into the darkness.
光らせて stage 作るから
I'll make the stage shine and build it,
だって君にもっと見てほしいから
because I want you to gaze at me even more.
give me crazy
まるで lazy?
like lazy?
次元混ざり合うの すべて塗り替える blue
Dimensions blending together, repainted blue.
手を上げて
Raise your hands,
clap your hands 海の向こうまで
clap your hands, across the sea,
clap your hands 届くように
clap your hands, may it reach you,
手を叩こう
let's clap our hands,
let's clap our hands!
ほら一緒に everybody
C'mon, together, everybody,
clap your hands 空の向こうまで
clap your hands, across the sky,
clap your hands 響きますように
clap your hands, may it resound,
手を叩こう
let's clap our hands,
let's clap our hands!
重なる wave
Let the overlapping wave
世界を揺らせ
shake the world!
光射す ぼくたちの未来
Light enters and illuminates our future.
お疲れ様でしたー！
Great job, everyone!
めちゃ緊張したー！
I was so nervous!
よかったねー
That went well!
はい、ということで、コラボ曲の最後の曲は、BLUE CLAPPERで、船長とぺこらちゃんとすばるちゃんとね、
Yes, so the final collaboration song was "BLUE CLAPPER," with Marine, Pekora, Subaru, and...
呼び出しちゃって歌いきれましたー！
we called them out and sang it all the way through!
わー！もう拍手おめでとうー！
Yay! Let's give a round of applause!
はい、そのね、４人はね、トワが勝手に、勝手にっていうかデビューして勝手に圧があると思ってた…
Yes, those four... Towa thought, well, not arbitrarily, but when we debuted, I felt a lot of pressure...
おかしくない？てこか？
Isn't that weird? Pekora?
え？圧があるってこと？
Huh? Pressure?
どこが圧があるんですか？
Where was there pressure?
だって、先輩と、マリンはわかるけどペこ...あれ？分からないだろ！
I mean, Senpai and Marine I get, but Peko... Huh? You wouldn't get it!
いやいや、個人的に、個人の展開がね、個人のがあったの。だからでもね、一緒にコラボしたりとかして、圧、圧でとかっていう話でコラボしてた、４人なのだから...
No, no, individually, everyone had their own developments. That's why, you know, we collaborated together, talking about pressure, since we're four people who...
感じられてるじゃん、ペこちゃん！
You can totally feel it, Pekora!
えも、えも、確かに！えもい！
Emo, emo, true! So emo!
ていうか、そういえば、エモい、エモいいつものやってもいいっすか？
Come to think of it, can we do our usual "emo" thing?
やろう、やろう！あるあるある！
Let's do it! Yeah, yeah!
じゃあ、お願いします！
Then, please!
あつれ、熱いよの！厚着ね！アツパープル！４人合わせて、アツレンジャー！
Hot, so hot! Thick clothes! Hot Purple! Four of us together, Hot Ranger!
と、誕生日！おめでとう！バイバーイ！
Happy birthday, Towa! Bye-bye!
おかしいだろそれ！ということで、あ、これ全部すばるちゃんがけないということで、お疲れ様でしたー！ばいばーい！
That's weird! Anyway, since Subaru couldn't write all this, great job, everyone! Bye-bye!
見える? この目の涙
Can you see? The tears in my eyes
命の色に滲んでいる
blurring with the colors of life
何を残して与えた?
What did you leave and give?
問いかけて潰れて
Questioning until it shatters
青と赤と白 混ざるこの世の中で
In this world where blue, red, and white mix,
叫んでいる
I am shouting
何を求めて歩いた?
What did I walk seeking?
追いかけて疲れて
Chasing after it until exhausted
どのくらい異常?
How abnormal is this?
壊れているの?
Am I breaking down?
壊れているよ
I am breaking down!
それでも息をしたいしたい
Even so, I want to breathe, to breathe
君に見えてるの?
Can you see it?
夢のように最後の言葉も詰まるよ
Like a dream, my final words choke up
ERROR
遠い日のこと 儚い光が
Things of a distant day, a fleeting light
空に溢れている
overflowing into the sky
何を選んで並べた?
What did I choose and line up?
涙色重ねて 浮かぶその身体
Layering tear-colors, that floating body
意識の中溶けて滲んでしまう
melting and blurring within consciousness
何を見てきて比べて
What did I see and compare?
悲しくって忘れて
Sad and forgetting,
どのくらい異常?
how abnormal is this?
歪んでいるの?
Is it distorted?
歪んでいるよ
It is distorted!
それでも息をしたいしたい 夢を見ているの?
Even so, I want to breathe, to breathe. Am I dreaming?
想う君に最後の言葉も詰まるよ ERROR
Thinking of you, my final words choke up. ERROR
与えることも失うことも忘れることもできないの暴れだすこのエラー
Can't I even give, lose, or forget? This error runs wild
殺して笑う僕がまたエラー
Laughing as it kills me, I'm an error again.
壊しているの?
Am I breaking down?
壊しているよ
I am breaking down!
それでも涙痛い痛い
Even so, tears hurt, hurt
君に届いたの?歌う声に
Did it reach you? With my singing voice
最後の言葉並べても 重なる日に沈んで
Even if I line up my final words, sinking into overlapping days.
壊しているの?
Am I breaking down?
壊しているよ
I am breaking down!
それでも息をしたいしたい 君に見えてたの?
Even so, I want to breathe, to breathe. Could you see it?
夢のように最後の言葉も詰まるよ ERROR
Like a dream, my final words choke up. ERROR
はーい、ということで、待って、ま、またということだって言ってしまった。
Hii, so— wait, I said 'so' again.
はーい、ERROR でした！ありがとうございました！
Hii! That was 'ERROR'! Thank you very much!
なんかコラボパートとソロで ERROR を歌っていただきました！
We had 'ERROR' sung in the collaboration part and solo!
やーい！なんと ERROR をね、あの、投稿してから約1年が経ちましたので
Yay! Somehow, about a year has passed since I posted 'ERROR',
ぜひまたね、あの、3Dライブの時に歌ったので、今日ねまたこうやって歌いたいなと思って歌うことができました！ありがとうございました！
so since I sang it at the 3D live, I wanted to sing it again today and I was able to! Thank you so much!
どう、どうでした？どうでした？
How, how was it? How was it?
いや、とわ、歌うまくなってる？
Man, Towa, are you getting better at singing?
勝手にね、歌が上手くなってると思っております。
I feel like my singing's gotten better on its own.
いやなんか、いや、すごい実感したな。
Man, like... yeah, I really felt that.
ひえーい。
Yaaay.
はい、というでね、あの、お時間も
So, you know, time is...
もう、なんと、もう何分？もう結構経ったよね。もう、もう50分も経っちゃって。
Already... wait, how many minutes? Quite a bit of time has passed. Like, already 50 minutes have passed.
はい。
Yeah.
なのでね、皆さん、こっからは、とは告知を、告知？
So everyone, from here on, Towa's announcement... announcement?
告知？をしたいなと思います。皆さんお気づきの通り！グッズが販売されます！
I'd like to make an announcement. As you all have noticed! Goods are going on sale!
はい、常闇トワ誕生日記念2021ということで、
Right, for Tokoyami Towa's Birthday Commemoration 2021,
なんと2種類出ます！抱き枕カバーとビビのスマートフォンベルトが、できます、出ます！
two types will be released! A hug pillow cover and a Bibi smartphone belt will be available, they'll be out!
ひえーい！なんか配信のね、あ、間違えた間違えた。えっと、画像の詳細をね出せますかね。
Yaaay! Wait, can I show the details of the image...
はい、そして、もらえるそうなんで。はい。あ、こっち。あ、こっち。
Right, and it looks like you can get... yeah. Ah, this way. Ah, this way.
はい、抱き枕カバーなんですが、Guchico先生に描いていただきました！
Right, for the hug pillow cover, Guchico-sensei drew it for us!
え、めっちゃ可愛くない？ねえ、見てよ。
Eh, isn't it super cute? Hey, look at that.
で、本当はさ、ちょっとね、ちょっとね、あのね、恥ずかしかった。恥ずかしかったんだけど、
Actually, you know, I was a little... a little embarrassed. I was embarrassed, but...
いや、出そう！記念だし、出そう！と思って、先生に描いてもらいました。めちゃめちゃ可愛くない？
I thought, "Let's put it out! It's a commemoration, let's release it!" and had sensei draw it. Isn't it super cute?
良くない？良くない？イェーイ、こんな感じで抱き枕カバーがこちらです。
Isn't it? Isn't it? Yay, here it is. That's the hug pillow cover.
はい、で、もう一つは、ビビのモチーフのスマートフォンベルトになってます。
Right, and the other one is a smartphone belt featuring Bibi.
これはね、男の子も女の子も使える、めっちゃんこおしゃれな、スマートフォンの持つベルト、スマートフォンにつけるベルトだね、になっております。
This is a super stylish smartphone belt that both boys and girls can use, a belt to hold or attach to your smartphone.
これをね、設置するとね、あのビビの顔がしっかり出てくるっていう感じのものになっております！
If you attach this, Bibi's face will pop right out, that kind of item!
で、この2つを、あの、一緒に購入してくれたセット、購入してくれた方には、直筆のメッセージ入りポストカードが数量限定でついてきます！
And for those who purchase these two together as a set, you'll get a postcard with a handwritten message in limited quantities!
じゃあ、メッセージが入ってないのもありよ。
Well, there's also one without a message.
はい、この後ね、9時から、9時からですよね。9時から販売されるので、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします！
Right, after this at 9 PM, it goes on sale at 9, right? It goes on sale from 9 PM, so please check it out!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はあ、ということでもね、もうこんなね、1時間っていうのは早いね。
Phew, so yeah, one hour goes by really fast.
なんかいろんなトワが魅せられたのかなと思います。ここ1年でね、本当に、もういろんな先輩たちや後輩とね、関わることが増えてきて、本当にトワは幸せ者だな、幸せ者だな！と思っております。本当にありがとうございます。
I think various sides of Towa were shown. In this past year, interacting with so many seniors and juniors has increased, and I really feel like Towa is such a fortunate, so fortunate person! I truly think so. Thank you so much.
みんなのありがとう！サンキュー、ありがとね！
Everyone, thank you! Thank you, thanks a lot!
はい、ではお時間も時間なので、最後の一曲歌って終わりたいと思います。
Right, since it's about time, I'd like to sing one final song and wrap things up.
では、聞いてください！
Now then, please listen!
想いの冒険を
An adventure of feelings,
忘れずに全部言えるかな
can I remember and say it all?
君から聞きたいよ
I want to hear it from you.
何回目の僕に出会った?
How many times have you met me?
僕は変わりました
I have changed.
新しい君に出会うために
To meet a new you,
久しぶりだねって言えたなら
if I could say "It's been a while,"
ここで泣こうか
should I cry right here?
好きとかって
Saying "I like you,"
嫌いとかって
saying "I hate you,"
何度だって愛を歌う君が恋しくって
I miss you, as you sing of love over and over,
嘘じゃない本当だよ、また出逢おう
it's not a lie, it's true, let's meet again.
僕らを嫌って「I」に戻って
Hating "II" and returning to "I",
何回だって間違ってきたよ
we've made mistakes so many times.
消えない後悔と冷めない愛情が
An unforgettable regret and unrelenting affection
想いの冒険を 忘れずに全部言えるかな
Can you recount our adventure of feelings, without forgetting a single detail?
君から聞きたいよ 何回目の僕に出会った?
I want to hear from you: How many times have we met now?
僕は変わりました 新しい君に出会うために
I've changed, to meet the new you.
久しぶりだねって 言えたならここで泣きそうか
If you could say: "Long time no see," I'd probably cry right here.
好きとかって 嫌いとかって
"I love you" or "I hate you"—
何度だって愛を歌う君が 恋しくって嘘じゃない本当だよ また出会おう
You sing of love time and time again. I miss you, and I'm not lying, it's the truth. Let's meet again.
想いの冒険は これからもちゃんと続いていく 3と9に乗って
The adventure of our feelings will continue on properly—riding on 3 and 9,
言葉とか飛び越えちゃって 君も変わりました
leaping past words and all! You've changed too,
新しい誰かに会うために 大人になりました
to meet someone new. I've grown up—
それだけでいいと思えた
and I felt that alone was enough.
好きとかって 嫌いとかって 何度だって愛を歌う君が 恋しくって嘘じゃない本当だよ また出会おう
"I love you" or "I hate you"—you sing of love time and time again. I miss you, and I'm not lying, it's the truth. Let's meet again.
はーい、ということで二回目の誕生日!
Right, so for my second birthday!
みんなとこうやって過ごせて 本当に本当に嬉しいです!
I'm so, so happy we get to spend it together like this!
“恋”をして…バカ。
Falling in love... dummy.
“愛”にして…バカ。
Turning it into love... dummy.
バカでいい この先も ずっとこのままだよ バカ。
It's fine to be dummies from here on out too, staying just like this... dummy.
僕らを“II”を嫌って“I”に戻って 何回だって間違ってきたよ
We hated "ii", came back to "i", and over and over again, we've made mistakes.
消えない後悔と 冷えない愛情が 恋を再起動する
Undying regret and warm affection reboot our love.
ほら“I”を嫌ってまた“II”に戻って “III”になって愛を繋いで行こう
See, we hated "i", came back to "ii" again, then it turned into "iii." Let's go on connecting our love.
言い得たい感情は 伝えたい正解は たったひとつだけ ありがとう
The feelings I want to express, the right answer I want to convey can be summed up in one thing: thank you.
ワンマイ愛を抱きたくないの もっとちゃんと恋にしてよ 妄想感情代償同盟 愛を懐いて理想を号泣んだ 行き場のある愛のメロディーを
I don't want to hold back my love, make it proper romance instead! Delusion, emotion, compensation alliance—clasping love and crying out for ideals, give us a melody of love that has somewhere to go!
今これまでにもありがとう
Thank you for everything up until now.
いつでも君と「こんな歌あったね」って 出会いを見数えられるように
So that whenever we say "There was a song like that," we can count all our meetings!